Let's go into some detail about how C++ uses RAM.
我们来详细介绍一下 C++ 如何使用 RAM
You can think of RAM as a set of slots where you can store information.
你可以将 RAM 视为一组用于存储信息的插槽
When your program executes data,
当你的程序运行数据时
it is usually stored in RAM.
数据通常存储在 RAM 中
This data can be overridden and in fact when you turn your computer off,
这些数据可以被覆盖 事实上 当你关闭电脑时
data in RAM is erased because RAM is volatile,
因为 RAM 是不稳定的 RAM 中的数据会被擦除
hence RAM is used for temporary storage.
因此 RAM 用于临时存储
Take a simple example like declaring a character variable,
举一个简单的例子 比如声明一个字符变量
when the x variable gets declared,
当 x 变量被声明时
your program will go into the computer's RAM and reserve space.
你的程序将进入计算机的 RAM 和预留空间
How much space will depend on the variable's type.
空间大小取决于变量类型
In the case of a character variable one byte gets reserved.
在字符变量的情况下 会保留一个字节
Then when the x variable gets defined,
然后 当 x 变量被定义时
the binary value for the character gets stored in RAM.
字符的二进制值存储在 RAM 中
In C++, the smallest unit of memory that your program can keep track of, is one byte.
在 C++ 中 程序可以跟踪的最小内存单元是一个字节
So what happens if your program defines another character variable.
那么 如果你的程序定义了另一个字符变量 会发生什么？
The compiler will then assign this character to the next available byte.
编译器会将这个字符分配给下一个可用的字节
And what about an integer variable,
那么 一个整数变量呢？
well a 32 bit integer would take up four bytes of memory.
一个 32 位整数将占用四个字节的内存
So an integer variable would take up four spaces in RAM,
所以一个整数变量在 RAM 中占用四个空格
the compiler and computer architecture will determine
编译器和计算机架构将决定
exactly how much space each variable needs in order to optimize the program.
每个变量需要多少空间才能优化程序
In general, the next variable gets placed above the previous variable.
一般来说 后一个变量放在前一个变量的上方
Each byte also has an address so that the program knows where to find the variable.
每个字节也有一个地址 方便程序知道在哪里找到变量
This entire area where C++ places variable values has a special name called the stack.
C++ 放置变量值的整个区域有一个特殊名称：栈
C++ uses the stack to efficiently manage reading and writing to memory for you.
C++ 使用堆栈来有效地管理读取和写入内存
When a function terminates and variables fall out of scope,
当函数终止并且变量超出范围时
the compiler freeze up or deallocates these memory locations working backwards.
编译器会冻结或反向操作 解除分配这些的内存位置
Besides the stack, the compiler offers other parts of memory for
除了栈之外 编译器还为不同的任务提供其他内存位置
different tasks like storing the text of
例如存储代码文本
your code and reserving space for global variables.
并为全局变量保留空间
C++ also provides an area of memory called the heap,
C++ 还提供了一个称为堆的内存区域
where you can manually control when a variable gets removed from memory.
在那里你可以手动控制变量何时从内存中移除
But how is all of this related to code optimization?
但是 这与代码优化有什么关系呢？
Reading from and writing to memory take time and thus can make your program slower.
因为从内存中读取和写入需要时间 这会拖慢程序
If you declare and define a variable that you don't actually need,
如果你声明并定义了一个你并不需要的变量
your program can slow down.
程序可能会变慢
If you copy a variable unnecessarily,
如果你进行了不必要的变量复制操作
your program can also slow down.
程序也会变慢
The stack also tends to be more efficient than the heap,
此外 栈一般也比堆更有效率
so how you declare your variables can end up affecting your program's performance.
所以 如何声明变量最终会影响程序的性能
Hence, the more you understand the consequences of each line of code,
因此 你越了解每行代码的影响
the better you can optimize.
优化效果就更好
That's what we mean when we talk about empathizing with the computer.
这就是我们为什么强调要学会以电脑的方式思考的原因了
Understanding the limitations of your hardware,
了解电脑硬件的限制
help to make better coding decisions.
有助于做出更好的编程决策